A Guide to the Lewis F. Powell Jr. Papers, 1929-1998
Washington and Lee University, School of Law, Lewis F. Powell, Jr. Archives
- Professional Associations 1937-1971
  - American Bar Association 1937-1971 (Box 52-81)
    - Meetings
      - Annual 1956-1971
        - London 1957
          - Notes 1957 (Box-folder 169/25)
          - Printed Materials 1957 (Box-folder 170/1)
          - Clippings, 1957 (Box-folder 170/2)
        - Los Angeles, 1958 (Box-folder 170/3)
        - Miami Beach, 1959 (Box-folder 170/4)
        - St. Louis, 1968 (Box-folder 170/5)
          Re Hunton & Williams Cocktail Party
        - Montreal, 1966 (Box-folder 170/6-9)
        - Houston (Mid-year), 1967 (Box-folder 170/10)
        - Hawaii, 1967 (Box-folder 170/11-14)
        - Atlanta (Winter, 1970 (Box-folder 170/15)
        - St. Louis, 1970 1969-1970 (Box-folder 170/16-18)
        - London, 1971
          - Correspondence
            - General 1967-1971 (Box-folder 170/19-33, Box-folder 171/1-15)
            - Planning Meetings
              - Dallas August 1969 (Box-folder 171/16)
              - St. Louis August 1970 (Box-folder 171/17-18)
              - London, November 8, 1970
            - Parties 1971 (Box-folder 171/20)
            - Programs of Sections and Committees, 1969-1971 (Box-folder 171/21-24)
            - Runnymede Ceremony, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 171/25-29)
            - Personal, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 172/1-3)
          - Subject Files
            - Agendas, 1968-1971 (Box-folder 172/4-12)
            - Invitations, 1971 (Box-folder 172/13)
            - Program, 1971 (Box-folder 172/14)
            - Lists, 1971 (Box-folder 172/15)
            - Memoranda, 1967-1971 (Box-folder 172/16)
            - Minutes, 1970 (Box-folder 172/17)
            - Reports, 1967-1970 (Box-folder 172/18)
            - Printed Materials, 1971 (Box 56)
            - Printed Miscellany, 1971 (Box-folder 172/19-23)
      - Regional
        - Richmond 1953 (Box-folder 173/1)
        - Atlanta 1958
          - Correspondence 1957-1958 (Box-folder 173/2-3)
          - Itineraries, Lists and Notes, 1958 (Box-folder 173/4)
          - Printed Materials, 1957-1958 (Box-folder 173/5)
        - Houston 1960 (Box-folder 173/6)
        - Little Rock 1962 (Box-folder 173/7-8)
        - Louisville 1957 (Box-folder 173/9-12)
        - Memphis, 1959
          - Correspondence, 1959 (Box-folder 173/13)
          - Printed Materials, 1959 (Box-folder 173/14)
        - Miami, 1959 (Box-folder 173/15-17)
        - New England, 1958
          - Correspondence, 1957-1959 (Box-folder 173/18-26, Box-folder 174/1-7)
          - Lists of Attendees, 1958 (Box-folder 174/8)
          - Printed Materials, 1956-1958 (Box-folder 174/9)
        - Pittsburgh, 1959
          - Correspondence, 1957-1959 (Box-folder 174/10-20)
          - Printed Materials, 1959 (Box-folder 174/21)
        - Portland 1960 (Box-folder 174/22)
        - St. Louis, 1958
          - Correspondence, 1957-1959 (Box-folder 174/23-30)
          - Printed Materials, 1958 (Box-folder 174/31)
    - Committees
      - Bill of Rights
        - Special 1941-1942 (Box-folder 175/1-4)
        - Standing
          - Correspondence 1949-1954 (Box-folder 175/5-10)
          - Subject Files
            - Subversive Activities, 1949-1951 (Box-folder 175/11)
            - Rights for Women 1945-1954 (Box-folder 175/12)
      - Centennial Commission 1967-1968
        - Correspondence, 1967-1969 (Box-folder 175/13-23)
        - Memoranda 1965-1968 (Box-folder 175/24-26)
        - Notes and Miscellany, 1967-68 (Box 58)
      - Continuing Legal Education, 1958-1966
        - Correspondence, 1959-1966 (Box-folder 175/28-40, Box-folder 176/1-6)
        - Memoranda, 1959-1964 (Box-folder 176/7-11)
        - Notes, 1958-1966 (Box-folder 176/12-15)
        - Reports, 1958-1962 (Box-folder 176/16-29)
        - Minutes, 1959-1962 (Box-folder 176/30-40, Box-folder 177/1-3)
        - Membership Lists, 1958-1959 (Box-folder 177/4)
        - Printed Materials, 1958-1961 (Box-folder 177/5)
      - Criminal Justice 1965-1972
        - Correspondence, 1965-1972 (Box-folder 177/6-27)
        - Memoranda
          - General, 1963-1970 (Box-folder 177/28-33, Box-folder 178/1-2)
          - by William A. Pusey, 1967-1969 (Box-folder 178/3-5)
          - by Powell, 1967-1970 (Box-folder 178/6-8)
        - Statement by Powell, 1968 (Box-folder 178/9)
        - Memoranda by Powell, 1969-1970 (Box-folder 178/10-11)
        - Membership Lists, 1965-1969
        - Statement by Powell, 1968 (Box-folder 178/12)
        - Printed Materials
          - General, 1966-1968 (Box-folder 178/13)
          - Draft Standards, 1967-1969 (Box-folder 178/14-17)
      - Economics of Law Practice
        - Correspondence
          - General, 1960-1966 (Box-folder 179/20, Box-folder 180/1-10)
          - Budget, 1961-1962 (Box-folder 180/11-12)
          - Expenses, 1960-1961 (Box-folder 180/13-16)
          - Regional Meetings, 1960-1962 (Box-folder 180/17-35, Box-folder 181/1-3)
          - Speeches, 1961-1962 (Box-folder 181/4-7)
        - Subject Files
          - Annual Legal Check-up, 1960-1962 (Box-folder 181/8-9)
          - Fee Limitations, 1960-1962 (Box-folder 181/10-15)
          - Fee Schedules, 1960-1962 (Box-folder 181/16-23)
          - Formation of Corporations
            - Correspondence, 1961-1962 (Box-folder 181/24-27)
            - Memoranda, 1961 (Box-folder 182/1-)
            - Printed Materials, 1961 (Box-folder 182/2)
          - The Lawyer's Handwork
            - Correspondence, 1960-1962 (Box-folder 182/3-20)
            - Memoranda and Minutes, 1961-1962 (Box-folder 182/21-23)
          - Partnership Pamphlet, 1959-1963 (Box-folder 182/28, Box-folder 183/1-11)
          - Survey of the Legal Profession
            - Correspondence, 1960-1962 (Box-folder 183/12-26)
            - Survey Instruments, 1961 & n.d. (Box-folder 183/27-28, Box-folder 184/1)
            - Memoranda and Notes, 1960-1962 (Box-folder 184/2-3)
            - Speeches, 1960-1961 (Box-folder 184/4)
            - Printed Materials, 1958-1963 (Box-folder 184/5)
          - Traffic Accident Compensation, 1960-1962 (Box-folder 184/6-9)
      - Education Against Communism, 1960-1971
        - Correspondence, 1960-1971 (Box-folder 184/11-27, Box-folder 185/1-23, Box-folder 186/1-28, Box-folder 187/1-21)
        - Memoranda, 1960-1961 & n.d. (Box-folder 187/22-31)
        - Speeches, 1961-1962 (Box-folder 187/27-34, Box-folder 188/1)
        - Conference On Education In Communism, 1961 (Box-folder 188/2)
        - Reports, 1961-1967 & n.d. (Box-folder 188/3-14)
        - Minutes, 1960-1971 (Box-folder 188/15-18)
        - Resolutions, 1960-1962 (Box-folder 188/19-23)
        - Handbook
          - Correspondence, 1961-1962 (Box-folder 188/24-30, Box-folder 189/1)
          - Printed Version, 1962 (Box-folder 189/2)
          - Memoranda, Press Releases and Book Review, 1961-1962 (Box-folder 189/3)
          - Distribution Lists and Letters, 1962 (Box-folder 189/4)
          - Bibliography, 1961 (Box-folder 189/5)
          - Typescript Drafts, 1961 (Box-folder 189/6)
        - Syllabus
          - Correspondence 1962-1964 (Box-folder 189/7-15)
          - West Publishing Essay Contest 1963 (Box-folder 190/1)
          - Notes, 1960-1964 (Box-folder 190/2)
          - Lists of Schools and Resources, 1960-1962 (Box-folder 190/3)
          - Research Materials
            - Near Print Materials, 1960-1966 & n.d. (Box-folder 190/4-9)
            - Printed Materials, 1958-1964 (Box-folder 190/10-12)
          - Newspaper Clippings, 1960-1962, 1967 (Box-folder 190/13-20, Box-folder 191/1-5)
      - Freedom of the Press and Freedom of Speech, 1951-1952 (Box-folder 191/6)
      - Hospitality, 1959-1960
        - Correspondence, 1959-1960 (Box-folder 191/7-18)
        - Memoranda, 1959-1960 (Box-folder 191/19-22)
        - Notes and Drafts, 1959-1960 (Box-folder 191/22)
        - Printed Materials, c. 1959 (Box-folder 191/23)
      - Legal Aid, 1959-1960 (Box-folder 191/24-27)
      - Membership 1946-1963
        - Correspondence, 1946-1963 (Box-folder 191/28-32, Box-folder 192/1-23)
        - Memoranda, 1955-1962 (Box-folder 192/24-27)
        - Notes and Drafts, 1955-1956 (Box-folder 192/28)
        - Reports, 1955-1956 (Box-folder 193/1-5)
        - Press Releases, 1966-1961 (Box-folder 193/6)
        - Lists, 1956-1962 & n.d. (Box-folder 193/7-10)
        - Printed Materials, 1956-1962 (Box-folder 193/11-13)
      - Public Utilities, 1938-1940
        - Correspondence, 1938-1940 (Box-folder 193/14-26)
        - Reports, 1939 (Box-folder 193/21)
        - Printed Materials, 1938 (Box-folder 194/22)
      - Regional Meetings, 1952-1962
        - Correspondence, 1952-1962 (Box-folder 194/1-33)
        - Memoranda, Minutes & Lists, 1958-1961 (Box-folder 194/34)
        - Reports, 1958-1961 (Box-folder 195/1-3)
        - Notes, 1958-1959 (Box-folder 195/4)
        - Papers re Pamphlet Revision, 1960 (Box-folder 195/5-6)
        - Blue & Gray Meeting, 1953 (Box-folder 195/7-10)
          - Papers and Reports, 1953 (Box-folder 195/11-13)
        - Printed Materials, 1953 (Box-folder 196/1-2)
      - Resolutions, 1960-61 (Box-folder 196/3)
      - Retirement Benefits, 1956-1965
        - Correspondence, 1956-1965 (Box-folder 196/4-28, Box-folder 197/1-3)
        - Memoranda, 1956-1962 (Box-folder 197/4-8)
        - Keough Bill, 1956-1960 (Box-folder 197/9-16)
        - Printed Materials, 1956-1960 (Box-folder 197/17)
      - World Peace Through Law, 1959-1962
        - Correspondence, 1959-1962 (Box-folder 197/18-23)
        - General Papers, 1959 & n.d. (Box-folder 197/24)
        - Speeches by Charles S. Rhyne, 1959-1960 (Box-folder 197/25)
        - Printed Materials, 1947-1961 (Box-folder 197/26)
    - Offices
      - Delegate, 1941-1963
        - Correspondence
          - General, 1941-1963 (Box-folder 197/27-34, Box-folder 198/1-21)
          - re ABA Politics, 1959-1962 (Box-folder 198/22-30)
        - Memoranda, 1958-1961 (Box-folder 198/31)
        - Reports, 1941-1942, 1957-1962 (Box-folder 198/35-36, Box-folder 199/1-5)
        - Lists, 1958-1959 (Box-folder 199/6)
        - Meeting Calendars, 1958-1961 (Box-folder 199/7-9)
        - Campaigns, 1953-1962
          - 1953 (Box-folder 199/10-14)
            - Correspondence, 1953 (Box-folder 199/10-14)
            - Petitons and Miscellaneous Documents, 1953 (Box-folder 199/15)
          - 1956
            - Biographical Information, 1956 (Box-folder 199/16)
            - General Correspondence, 1956-1957 (Box-folder 199/1-26, Box-folder 200/1-10)
            - Correspondence re Petitions, 1956-1957 (Box-folder 199/1-26, Box-folder 200/11-15)
            - re Tucker & Mays Letter, 1956-1957 (Box-folder 200/16-18)
            - Draft Letters, 1956-1957 (Box-folder 200/19)
            - Memoranda, 1956-1957 (Box-folder 200/20)
            - Lists, 1956-1957 (Box-folder 201/1)
            - Petitions, 1956 (Box-folder 201/2)
          - 1959
            - Correspondence, 1958-1959 (Box-folder 201/3-6)
            - Petitions, 1959 (Box-folder 201/7)
          - 1962
            - Correspondence
              - General, 1961-1962 (Box-folder 201/8)
              - Gibson and Moore, 1961-1962 (Box-folder 201/9)
            - Memoranda, 1961-1962 (Box-folder 201/10)
            - Petitions, 1962 (Box-folder 201/11)
        - Printed Materials, 1941-1942, 1957-1960 (Box-folder 201/12)
      - Board of Governors, 1962-1965
        - Correspondence
          - General, 1962-1964 (Box-folder 202/1-7)
          - Amendment of By-Laws, 1963 (Box-folder 202/8)
          - Law Day Committee, 1962-1965 (Box-folder 202/17)
          - Liaison with Committees and Sections, 1962-1963 (Box-folder 202/21)
          - Subcommittee on Washington Office, 1963 (Box-folder 202/22)
        - Agenda 1962 (Box-folder 202/23)
        - Summary of Actions, February 4-5, 1963 (Box-folder 202/24)
        - Memoranda, Statements and Notes, 1963 (Box-folder 202/25)
        - Proceedings, 1962-1963 (Box-folder 202/26-27, Box-folder 203/1-3)
        - Law Day Committee
          - Statements and Ads, 1964-1965 (Box-folder 203/4)
          - Printed Materials, 1962-1965 (Box-folder 203/5)
          - Subcommittee on Washington Office, Reports and Memoranda, 1963 (Box-folder 203/6)
      - President-Elect 1955-1964
        - Ross Malone Candidacy, 1955-1958 (Box-folder 203/7-13)
        - Powell Campaign, 1959-1963
          - Correspondence
            - General, 1959-1963 (Box-folder 203/14-18, Box-folder 204/1-19)
            - Francis W. Hill
              - General, 1962 (Box-folder 204/20-23, Box-folder 205/1-2)
              - Responses to His March 19, 1962 Letter, 1962 (Box-folder 205/3)
            - Thomas B. Gay, 1962 (Box-folder 205/4-7)
          - Memoranda and Draft Letters, 1961-1962 (Box-folder 205/8)
          - Resolutions, 1963 (Box-folder 205/9)
          - Miscellaneous Documents, 1961-1962 (Box-folder 205/10)
        - Correspondence, 1963-1964
          - Congratulatory
            - Incoming Letters, 1963 (Box-folder 205/11-19, Box-folder 206/1-5)
            - Outgoing Letters, 1963 (Box-folder 206/5-11)
          - General, 1963-1964 (Box-folder 206/12-22, Box-folder 207/1-12)
          - Subject Correspondence
            - Budget and Financial, 1963-1965 (Box-folder 207/13-16)
            - Civil Rights, 1963-1964 (Box-folder 207/17)
            - Committee Appointments, 1963-1964 (Box-folder 207/18-24, Box-folder 208/1-7)
            - Criminal Justice, 1963-1964 (Box-folder 208/8-12)
            - Presidential Succession, 1963-1964 (Box-folder 208/13-18)
            - Speeches, 1963-1964 (Box-folder 208/18-22)
            - Warren Commission, 1964-1965 (Box-folder 208/23-27)
        - Memoranda and Reports, 1964 (Box-folder 208/28-32)
        - Subject Files, 1963-1965
          - Audits and Budgets (Box-folder 208/33)
          - Bail (Box-folder 208/34)
          - Board of Governors, Proceedings (Box-folder 209/1-2)
          - Civil Rights (Box-folder 209/3)
          - Committee Appointments (Box-folder 209/4)
          - Criminal Justice (Box-folder 209/5)
          - Greece Trip (Box-folder 209/6)
          - Presidential Succession (Box-folder 209/7-9, Box-folder 210/1)
          - Schedules (Box-folder 210/2)
          - Warren Commission (Box-folder 210/3)
      - President 1964-1965
        - Correspondence
          - General 1964-1965 (Box 210-212, Box-folder 213/1-9)
          - Congratulatory, 1964
            - Incoming (Box-folder 213/10-13)
            - Outgoing (Box-folder 213/14-18)
          - w. U.S. Presidential Candidates, 1964 (Box-folder 213/19)
          - re Leaving Presidency, 1965 (Box-folder 213/20-25)
          - Crank Letters, 1965 (Box-folder 213/26-27)
        - Memoranda and Reports, 1964-1965 (Box-folder 213/28-30, Box-folder 214/1-2)
        - Subject Files, 1964-1965
          - ABA Directories, 1965 (Box-folder 214/3)
          - Annual Meeting, 1965 (Box-folder 214/4-30, Box-folder 215/1-3)
          - (Melvin) Belli Complaint, 1964-1965 (Box-folder 215/4-9)
          - Board of Governors, 1964-1965 (Box-folder 215/10-13, Box-folder 216/1-4)
          - Civil Rights, 1964-1965 (Box-folder 216/5-8)
          - Criminal Justice Project, 1964-1965 (Box-folder 217/1-11)
          - Dodd Firearms Bill, 1965 (Box-folder 217/12)
          - Estes v. Texas, 1964-1965 (Box-folder 217/13-16)
          - Ethics Evaluation, 1964-1965 (Box-folder 217/17-25)
          - Inter-American Bar Association Meeting, 1964 (Box-folder 218/1)
          - Jurisprudence and Law Reform, 1964-1965 (Box-folder 218/2-3)
          - Lawyer Referral, 1964-1965 (Box-folder 218/4-8)
          - Legal Aid and Indigent Defendants, 1964-1965 (Box-folder 218/13)
          - Magna Carta Ceremony - London, 1964-1965 (Box-folder 218/14-28, Box-folder 219/1-13)
          - Presidential Succession (25th Amendment), 1964-1965 (Box-folder 219/14-22)
          - Proposed Committee on Availability of Legal Services, 1965 (Box-folder 219/26)
          - Proposed Section on Individual Rights, 1965 (Box-folder 219/27-29)
          - Mid-Winter Meeting - New Orleans, 1965 (Box-folder 219/30)
          - Regional Meeting - Puerto Rico, 1964-1965 (Box-folder 219/31-35, Box-folder 220/1-6)
          - Schedules, 1964-1965 (Box-folder 220/7)
          - Speaking Engagements, 1964-1965 (Box-folder 220/8-13)
          - Substantive Tax Reform, 1964-1965 (Box-folder 220/14-16)
          - War On Poverty/Group Legal Services, 1964-1965 (Box-folder 220/17-25, Box-folder 221/1-12)
        - Speeches, 1964-1965, In two bound volumes. (Box-folder 222/1-2)
        - Printed Materials, 1964-1965
          - General, 1964-1965 (Box-folder 223/1)
          - American Bar News, 1963-1965 (Box-folder 223/2)
          - News From the American Bar Association, 1964-1965 (Box-folder 223/3)
          - Washington Letter, 1963-1965 (Box-folder 223/4)
        - Clippings, 1964-1965
          - General, 1963-1965 (Box-folder 223/5-14)
          - Selected Clippings and Letters, Lewis F. Powell, Jr., President, American Bar Association, 1964-1965, Bound in volume - 2 copies. (Box-folder 223/15, Box-folder 224/1)
  - American Bar Foundation 1960-1971 (Box 82-83)
    American Bar Foundation series includes two subseries: general papers and papers about Powell's presidency from 1969-1971. The relationship of the American Bar Foundation to the American Bar Association is a frequent topic in these papers.
    - Correspondence
      - General, 1960-1968 (Box-folder 225/1-10)
      - re Fellows, 1957-1967 (Box-folder 225/24)
    - ABF By-Laws and Articles of Incorporation, 1961-1970 (Box-folder 225/25)
    - Research Committee Meetings, 1961 (Box-folder 225/26-27)
    - Fellows
      - Nominating Committee, 1958-1960 & n.d. (Box-folder 226/1)
      - Lists of Fellows, 1961-1971 (Box-folder 226/2)
    - President, 1969-1970
      - Correspondence, 1969-1971 (Box-folder 226/3-19, Box-folder 227/1-10)
      - Memoranda, 1969-1971 (Box-folder 227/11)
      - Notes and Drafts, 1969-1971 (Box-folder 227/12)
      - Reports, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 227/13)
      - Subject Files
        - ABF/ABA Relationship
          - Correspondence, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 227/14-20)
          - Memoranda and Reports, 1970 (Box-folder 227/21)
      - Annual Meetings, 1970 (Box-folder 227/22)
      - Bar Center Building, 1971 (Box-folder 227/23-24)
      - Budget and Fiscal, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 227/25)
      - Committee On Extramural Research, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 228/1-2)
      - Executive Director Selection, 1968-1972 (Box-folder 228/3-8)
    - Board Meetings: Agenda and Exhibits, 1969-1971 (Box-folder 228/10-11, Box-folder 229/1-3)
    - Printed Materials, 1962-1971 & n.d. (Box-folder 229/4)
  - American College of Trial Lawyers 1958-1971
    American College of Trial Lawyers series is similar in content and arrangement to the ABF series. A significant difference is that the papers from Powell's time as president of this organization (1969-1970) are not segregated from those concerning his general membership. Subseries include: correspondence, 1958-1971; committees; meetings; subject files; and printed materials.
    - Correspondence, 1961-1966 (Box-folder 229/5-13, Box-folder 230/1-13)
    - Board of Regents
      - Correspondence
        - General, 1967-1969 (Box-folder 230/14-28)
        - Election of Members, 1968-1970 (Box-folder 230/29)
        - Emeritus Fellowship, 1965-1968 (Box-folder 231/1-2)
      - Notes, Reports and Minutes, 1968-1969 (Box-folder 231/3)
    - Committees, 1967-1969 (Box 84)
      - Ball v. ATLA, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 231/4-8)
      - Civil Trial Practice Manual, 1965-1970 (Box-folder 231/9-16)
      - Liaison with British Bar, 1971 (Box-folder 231/17)
      - Nominating Procedures, 1970 (Box-folder 231/18-19)
      - Proposed Federal Rules of Evidence, 1969-1970 (Box-folder 231/20-23)
      - Specialization, 1969 (Box-folder 231/24)
      - State Committees, 1968-1971
        - Correspondence, 1968-1970 (Box-folder 231/25-28)
        - Assignments, 1969-1970 (Box-folder 231/29)
        - North Carolina Nominees, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 231/30)
        - Virginia Nominees, 1969-1971 (Box-folder 231/31-33)
    - Meetings, 1967-1970 (Box-folder 232/1-22, Box-folder 233/1-4)
    - Subject Files
      - Grant Cooper, 1969-1970 (Box-folder 233/5-7)
      - Disruption of Trials
        - Correspondence, 1970 (Box-folder 233/8-12)
        - Statements, Reports and Clippings, 1970 (Box-folder 233/13)
      - Lists, 1966-1971 (Box-folder 233/14)
      - Minutes, 1969-1971 (Box-folder 233/15-16)
      - Panel on Human Transplants, 1968-1969 (Box-folder 233/17-18)
      - Presidents Manual, c. 1970 (Box-folder 233/19)
    - Printed Materials, 1967-1971 (Box-folder 233/20)
  - American Judicature Society 1958-1963
    - Correspondence, 1958-1963 (Box-folder 233/21-26)
    - Membership Campaign
      - Correspondence, 1959 (Box-folder 233/27-28)
      - Member Lists and Letter Drafts, 1958-1959 (Box-folder 234/1)
    - Minutes, Charters and By-laws, 1959-1962 (Box-folder 234/2)
    - Memoranda, Reports and Press Releases, 1958-1961 (Box-folder 234/3)
    - Printed Materials, 1959-1961 (Box-folder 234/4)
  - American Law Institute 1947-1967
    - General Correspondence, 1947-1967 (Box-folder 234/1-8)
    - Printed Materials, 1947-1956 (Box-folder 234/9)
  - Association of Life Insurance Counsel 1957-1963 (Box-folder 234/10)
  - National Center for State Courts 1971
    National Center for State Courts treats Powell's membership on the steering committee of this organization. The committee was responsible for organizing the center as a nonprofit corporation. This work included preparing the charter and determining the method of trustee selection.
    - Correspondence, 1971 (Box-folder 234/11-13)
    - Memoranda, 1971 (Box-folder 234/14)
    - Printed Materials, 1971 (Box-folder 234/15)
  - Richmond Bar Association 1946-1966
    Richmond Bar Association (known as the Bar Association of the City of Richmond until around 1960) series is less than four inches of correspondence and records. In addition to a twenty year run of general correspondence, there is correspondence about Powell's role in the successful 1954 campaign to have his law school classmate, Walter E. Hoffman, nominated for the newly created position of U.S. District Judge for the Eastern District of Virginia. The general correspondence for 1947-1948 deals with Powell's service as president during that time.
    - Correspondence
      - General, 1947-1956 (Box-folder 234/16-25)
      - re Walter E. Hoffman Judicial Appointment, 1954 (Box-folder 234/26)
    - Statements, Reports and Resolutions, 1947-1968 (Box-folder 234/27)
    - Charter, By-Laws and Related Materials, 1938, 1958 & n.d. (Box-folder 234/28)
    - Printed Materials and Miscellaneous Documents, 1947-1948 & n.d. (Box-folder 234/29)
  - Virginia State Bar Association 1948-1970
    Virginia State Bar Association series is one foot of correspondence, committee files and printed materials. Powell served on the Executive Committee and also co-chaired the committee that planned the ceremony at Jamestown (May 1959) commemorating the advent of common law in North America in 1607. The committee's work is thoroughly documented in this series. Records of Powell's other committee work are here, as is a run of general correspondence spanning the years 1948-1970.
    - Correspondence
      - General, 1946-1970 (Box-folder 235/1-16)
      - Advent of Common Law - Jamestown, 1958-1960 (Box-folder 235/17-26)
    - Committees
      - Continuing Legal Education
        - Correspondence, 1959-1962 (Box-folder 235/27-28, Box-folder 236/1-7)
        - Minutes, 1959-1961 (Box-folder 236/8)
        - Proposals, Memoranda and Notes, 1959-1960 & n.d. (Box-folder 236/9)
      - Executive